Guide to the Archie Ammons papers,1945-2010.
Ammons, Archie papers, 1945-2010.
- Series IX. Critical Reception
  - Clippings
    - News clippings, 1998-2001 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - Ads for Events or Publications
    - Announcements and publicity: Posters, events' programmes, flyers, ads for publications (Box 89)
    - Announcements and publicity: Posters, events' programmes, flyers, ads for publications, 1985, 1993-1996 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Announcements and publicity: Posters, events' programmes, flyers, ads for publications, 1998 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Announcements and publicity: Posters, events' programmes, flyers, ads for publications, undated (Box 123, Folder 10)
- Series X. Writings and Works by Others
  - Essays and poetry by: Abrams, Doug (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Mike (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Coleman, Elliott (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Fosso, D. R. (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Kessler, Milton (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Miles, Josephine (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Piasecki, Bruce (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Tanenhaus, Beverly (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Tharaud, Ross (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - West, Jean (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Students' poems (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Various authors (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Announcements, magazine issues, drawings, photographs (Box 92)
  - "A Poem for Archie Ammons" musical score by K. Frazelle, 1988 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - "Two American Songs" musical score by Nancy Blomer Deussen, 1988 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    1. The Long Voyage 2. The River
  - Letter press edition of "Stand-In" by J. Tyler, 1994n (Box 116, Folder 7)
    Drawings by J. Tyler. 4 copies 2 signed by Archie Ammons
- Series XI. Photographs, Memorabilia, and Artwork
  - Assorted photographs in color and black and white (Box 93)
  - Memorabilia: Personal effects and mementos (Box 94)
  - Memorabilia related to awards (Box 95)
  - Artwork by Archie Ammons: four paintings (Box 96)
  - Artwork by Archie Ammons: one drawing and fourteen watercolors. Includes a draft of the invitation to the art show, prepared by A.R. Ammons. (Box 97)
  - Framed artwork/poem by Ammons, undated (Box 115)
    "I found a weed that had a mirror in it and that mirror looked in at a mirror in me that had a weed in it"
  - Panorama photograph of Ammons' Navy Company and a Print of the "Baltimore Beech", 1944, 2000 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Print of Zapatistas by Jose Clemente Orozco, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - 5 watercolors by Archie Ammons, 1977, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - 7 watercolors by Archie Ammons, 1977, 1979 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Framed cartoon from the June 1968 issue of Playboy, 1994 (Box 117)
    Inscription on the back reads "To Archie Ammons with regards from Pete Curtiss. From the June 1968 issue of Playboy. March 29, 1994"
  - Photograph and contact prints, undated (Box 124)
  - 21 small watercolors by Ammons, 1983, undated (Box 129, Folder 17)
    one with typed poem
  - 51 watercolors by Ammons, 1968, 1977-1982, 1987-1989 (Box 131)
  - 5 watercolor paintings by Ammons, 1971, 1982 (Folder 1)
  - Pastel by H.J. Lovelle, Undated (Folder 2)
- Series XII. Books and Magazines
  - Works by A.R. Ammons (poetry, essays):
    - Highgate Road The Inkling Press, Ithaca, NY, undated (Box 98)
      3 copies, printed by Tim Larkin and signed by Ammons
    - Six-Piece Suite Palaemon Press Limited, 1978 (Box 98)
      Hand bound. 230 copy edition. 2 copies - copy inscribed to Phyllis and signed and the other unbound and unsigned
    - Poem Press for Privacy, Winston-Salem, NC, undated (Box 98)
      Sixty copy edition. Single poem in small envelope. 9 copies signed by Ammons
    - "Establishment", c. 1985 (Box 98)
      this end up postcard
    - "Breaking Out" broadside, 1978 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      126 copy edition by Palaemon with illustration by Ammons. 14 copies.
    - "Rarities" broadside, 1994 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      126 copy edition by Larch Tree Press with illustrations by J. Tyler. 2 copies signed by Ammons.
    - "Easter Morning", 1986 (Box 98)
      220 copy edition printed by the Shadowy Waters Press for the North Carolina Humanities Committee. 5 copies signed by Ammons
    - The Really Short Poems of A.R. Ammons, 1990 (Box 98)
    - The North Carolina Poems, 1994 (Box 98)
      Signed by Ammons
    - The First Anthology edited by A.R. Ammons, Deborah Auer, Carol Burke, Rachel Davis, Julie Kane, Bruce Piasecki, Ross Tharaud, 1974 (Box 98)
    - The Best American Poetry 1994 edited by A.R. Ammons, 1994 (Box 98)
      Uncorrected advance proof. Signed by David Lehman, series editor.
    - The North Carolina Poems, 1994 (Box 98)
    - "Quick Song" No Business Poems p.1, undated (Box 99)
    - "Bridge," Gravelly Run," "Visit," and "Corson's Inlet" The Contemporary American Poets pp.29-36, 1969 (Box 100)
    - "Eyesight" Epitaphs for Lorine, 1973 (Box 100)
    - "He Held Radical Light," Gravelly Run," "Corson's Inlet," "Reflective," "Terrain," and "The City Limits" The Vintage Book of Contemporary American Poetry pp. 278-286, 1990 (Box 100)
    - "Constant" and "Cut the Grass" Western Wind: An Introduction to Poetry p539-541, 1992 (Box 100)
      Signed by the editor.
    - "Bridge," "Gravelly Run," "Visit," and "Corson's Inlet" The Contemporary American Poets pp.1-8, 1969 (Box 100)
      Signed by Ammons.
    - "Dunes" and "Corson's Inlet" Possibilities of Poetry: An Anthology of Contemporaries pp.319-323, 1970 (Box 100)
    - "Room Conditioner" Tendril Magazine presents: The Poet's Choice, 100 American Poets' Favorite Poems p. 18, 1980 (Box 100)
    - "Standing Light Up," "Looking Way Off," "Somers Point,"First Cold," and "White Echo" Poems for a Small Planet: Contemporary American Nature Poetry pp.9-12, 1993 (Box 100)
    - "Serpent Country" Ecstatic Occasions, Expedient Forms: 85 Leading Contemporary Poets Select and Comment on Their Poems pp. 1-2, 1996 (Box 100)
    - "Zero and Then Some" New North Carolina Poetry: The Eighties pp. 18-19, 1982 (Box 100)
      With program for "Poetry-in-the-Round" at Seton Hall University, October 7, 1985 tipped into the page.
    - "Coon Song" Poetry to Read Out Loud p. 169, 1993 (Box 100)
    - Albright, Alex, "Ponds and Mudbanks, and Ditchbanks, Brierberries, Things of That Kind: A Conversation with A.R. Ammons," with excerpts from "Tape for the End of the Year," and the poem "Broad Brush" North Carolina Literary Review Vol. 1 No. 1 (Summer 1992) pp. 7, 46. (Box 101)
    - "Alligator Holes Down Along About Old Dock," North Carolina Literary Review," vol. I, no. 2 (Spring 1993) p. 228. (Box 101)
    - "Antithesis," "Range," and "Sweetened Change," The Hampden-Syndney Poetry Review (Winter 1979) pp. 1-3. (Box 101)
    - "A.R. Ammons: Interview and Poems," with "The Fairly High Assimilation Rag," and "The Spiral Rag," The Manhattan Review vol. 1, no. 2 (Fall 1980) pp. 1-34. (Box 101)
    - "The Arts," Country Club Woman (November/December 1960) pp. 44-55. (Box 101)
    - "Boon," The New Republic (August 1, 1988) p. 48 (Box 101)
    - "The Brook Has Worked Out the Prominence of a Bend," and "Strolls," Poetry, vol. CXXXIII, no. 1 (November 1978) pp. 80-81. (Box 101)
    - "By the Boulder Cluster the Wind," The Hudson Review, vol. XXX, no. 3 (Autumn 1977) pp. 371. (Box 101)
    - "Candle-lit," The Harvard Review, no. 9 (Fall 1995) p. 34. (Box 101)
    - "Changing Stations," Moosehead Review, no. 6 (1982) p. 6. (Box 101)
    - "Chiseled Clouds," broadside included in commemorative brochure on Epoch, 1985. (Box 101)
    - "Coming Round," Carolina Quarterly, vol. 37, no. 3 (Spring 1985) p. 34. (Box 101)
    - "Coming Clearing," "Anxiety's Prosody," "The Surprise of an Ending," and "All's All," Poetry, vol. CXLIII, no. 1 (October, 1988) pp. 1-4. (Box 101)
    - "Commentary," Poets and Writers, vol. 15, no. 2 (March/April 1987) p. 16. (Box 101)
    - "Commissary," Prairie Schooner, vol. 62, no. 2 (Summer 1988) p. 36. (Box 101)
    - "Cornell's Wee Stinkie," Ackee, no. 2 (June 1994) p. 33. (Box 101)
    - "Corsonsundet," Tarningskastet, no. 6, 1980, pp. 33-38. (in Swedish). (Box 101)
    - "Country Music," Michigan Quarterly Review, vol. XVII, no. 4 (Fall 1978) p. 457. (Box 101)
    - "Day Ghosts," The New Yorker, April 15, 1985, p. 49. (Box 101)
    - "December Starlings," Beloit Poetry Journal, vol. 45, no. 4, p. 7. (Box 101)
    - "The Deep Slow," "Spot Check," and "Sparklings," Grand Street, vol. 7, no. 4 (Summer 1988) pp. 81-83. (Box 101)
    - "Distraction," "Design," "Rapids," "Feel like Traveling On," and "Spruce Woods," The Hudson Review, vol. XXXIII (Spring 1980) pp. 35-37. (Box 101)
    - "Easter Morning," Poetry, no. 1, vol. CXXXIV (April 1979) pp. 1-4. (Box 101)
    - "Enameling" and "Walking Around in the Evening," Cornell Review (Fall 1979) p. 74 (Box 101)
    - "Extravaganza," Abraxas, vol. 21/22, 12th Anniversary Issue, p. 3. (Box 101)
    - "First Loves," Journal of the Poetry Society of America, no. 49 (Spring 1997) p. 9. (Box 101)
    - "Flat Rock," North Carolina Literary Review, no. 5, vol. II (1996) p. 70. (Box 102)
    - "For Emily Wilson from a Newcomer," Chelsea, no. 55, p. 13. (Box 102)
    - "Front," Foxfire, no. 1, vol. 2 (March 1968) p. 51. (Box 102)
    - "Getting About," "Saving Account," and "Generally Clear with Scattered Slippery Spots," Panoply, no. 1, vol. 2 (Winter/Spring 1988) pp. 64-66. Includes note by Timothy Houghton. (Box 102)
    - "Going Places," Pearl, no. 14 (Winter 1993) p. 4. (Box 102)
    - "Gravelly Run," "Epiphany," and "Mansion," Poetry, no. 2, vol. XCVII (November 1960) pp. 94-97. (Box 102)
    - "The Hermit Lark," Imprint, no. 2, 1980, p. 31. (Box 102)
    - "The High Desiring,"The Grapevine's Finger Lakes Magazine (Winter 1986-87) p. 70. (Box 102)
    - "An Improvisation for the Pieties of Modernism," "An Improvisation for Angular Momentum," and "An Improvisation for Soot and Suet," Poetry, no. 1, vol. CLIX (October 1991) pp. 1-4. (Box 102)
    - "Inclinations," The Hudson Review, no. 1, vol. XL (Spring 1987) pp. 59-70. (Box 102)
    - "Keeping Track," North Carolina Literary Review, no. 1, vol. II (Spring 1994) p. 21. (Box 102)
    - "Laser," Foxfire, no. 1, vol. 1 (March 1967) p. 32. Includes note by Eliot Wigginton. (Box 102)
    - "Late Look," Mississippi Review, no. 7, vol. 3 (Fall 1978) p. 27. (Box 102)
    - "A Little Thing Like That," Bound, September 1986. (Box 102)
    - "Lofty Calling," "Obsession," "Weightlessness," and Walsh, William, "An Interview with A.R. Ammons," Michigan Quarterly Review, no. 1, vol. XXVIII (Winter 1989) pp. 105-120. (Box 102)
    - "Long Sorrowing," The New Yorker, October 20, 1986, p. 48. (Box 102)
    - "Louise," Granite, no. 4 (Autumn 1972-73) p. 95. (Box 102)
    - "Love songs,"Poetry, no. 3, vol. 110 (June 1967) n.p. (Box 102)
    - "Middling Seasons," "Whitewater," and "Spike-Tooth Harrows," The Yale Review, vol. 80, no. 4 (October 1992) pp. 37-39. (Box 102)
    - "Modes Against Too Much," "Death and Silhouettes," "The Crystal Tree," The Paris Review, no. 127 (Summer 1993) pp. 34-37. (Box 103)
    - "Moving Figures," and "Prisons There and Not," Tar River Poetry, vol. 33 (Fall 1993) pp. 144-46. (Box 103)
    - "Museums," and "Time Being," Partisan Review, no. 1, vol. LVIII (Winter 1991) pp. 118-19. (Box 103)
    - "Narrows," Chicago Review. 26th Anniversary Poetry Issue, no. 3, vol. 26, p. 63. (Box 103)
    - "Now Then," Michigan Quarterly Review, no. 1, vol. XXXVI (Winter 1997) 185-187. (Box 103)
    - "Ontology Precedes Teleology," Skylark, XVII Issue, 1988-89, p. 7. (Box 103)
    - "Pairing" and "Course Discourse," Brim: An Arts Journal, no. 4 (Fall 1975) p. 18. (Box 103)
    - "A Part for the Whole," South-West Review, Spring 1987, p. 39. (Box 103)
    - "Period," Columbia: A Magazine of Poetry and Prose, no. 20 (Summer 1993) pp. 26-7. (Box 103)
    - "Persistences," Poetry, no. 2, vol. CXXXII (May 1978) p. 88. (Box 103)
    - "Picking Up Equations"The Paris Review, no. 134 (May 1978) p. 221. (Box 103)
    - "Ping Jockeys," Princeton University Library Chronicle, no. 3, vol. LV (Spring 1994) p. 468. (Box 103)
    - "A Pretty Looking Sight," Bluefish, no. 1, vol. 1 (Autumn 1983) p. 2. (Box 103)
    - "Prey," Poetry, January 1996, p. 206. (Box 103)
    - "Providences" Granite, no. 7/8 (Spring 1974) p. 118. (Box 103)
    - "Radiant Days," CrossRoads: A Journal of Southern Culture, no. 1, vol. 1 (Fall 1992) pp. 45-48. (Box 103)
    - "Reading Ta'o Chien," The Southern Review, Autumn 1994, p. 791. (Box 104)
    - "Readings By Ways," Partisan Review, no. 4, vol. LV (1988) p. 611. (Box 104)
    - "Remembering Old Caves," "Tertiaries" Bound, no. 2 (April 1987) n.p. (Box 104)
    - "Righting Wrongs," Ubu, no. 3, p. 5. (Box 104)
    - "Room Conditioner" Tendril Poetry, no. 2 (Spring-Summer 1978) n.p. (Box 104)
    - "Rosalie" The New Republic, March 7, 1988, p. 34. (Box 104)
    - "The Sale Sale," "Blues in the Valley," "Turning Things Out Good," and "For My Beloved Son," The Hudson Review, no. 1, vol. XLVI (Spring 1993) p. 169-172. (Box 104)
    - "Saying Saying Away" and "The Clenched-Jaw School," Poetry, no. 3, vol. CLXVIII (June 1996) pp. 133-134. (Box 104)
    - "Second-Rate Perfection," Banyan, vol. 1, 1990, p. 6. (Box 104)
    - "A Sense of Now," "Emerging Curves," "Local Antiquities," "Sumerian Vistas," "Collapsed Structures," and "The Deep End," Poetry, no. 1, vol. CLXVIII (April 1996) pp. 1-7. (Box 104)
    - "Sentiment," The New Yorker, February 21, 1994, p. 76. (Box 104)
    - "The Separation" and "Pit Lines," St. Andrews Review, no. 34 (Spring/Summer 1988) pp. 67-68. (Box 104)
    - "September Drift," "Mountain Talk," "Here & Now," "Square," "Admission," "Cougar," "Project," "Reversal," "Dominion," "Countering," "Working Still," "Then One," and "Play," Poetry, no. 1, vol. CXVII (October 1970) pp. 7-19. (Box 104)
    - "Singling and Doubling Together," "Meeting Place," "Yadkin Picnic," Poetry, no. 1, vol. CXLI (October 1982) pp. 1-4. (Box 104)
    - "Some Notes on William Harmon, 'Paronomastics,'" in Connotations, no. 1, vol. 3, 1993, pp. 42-43. (Box 104)
    - "Spiritual Progress" Yale Review, Autumn 1981, p. 88. (Box 104)
    - "Spring Tornado," "Certainty," "Model," and "Self-Projection," New Letters, no. 2, vol. 39 (Winter 1972) pp. 75-76. (Box 104)
    - "Standing Light Up," and "Plain Divisions," Verse, Issue 3, p. 3. (Box 104)
    - "Strings," Tar River Poetry, no. 1, vol. 28 (Fall 1988) pp. 60-61. (Box 104)
    - "From Strip," The Paris Review, no. 139 (Summer 1996) pp. 106-109. (Box 104)
    - "Summer Place," The Hudson Review, no. 2, vol. XXX (Summer 1977) pp. 173-209. (Box 105)
    - "Sung Reassertions," The Beloit Poetry Journal, (Fall 1963) p. 36. (Box 105)
    - "Taking Place" and "Contruing Deconstruction" Verse, no. 4, p. 8. (Box 105)
    - "Time After Time," "The Incomplete Life," and "What Was That Again," The Ohio Review, no. 41, 1988, 105-107. (Box 105)
    - "Volitions" Sparrow, no. 1 (Fall 1979) p. 8. (Box 105)
    - "I Went Back," "Immortality," "Warming Trend" Beloit Poetry Journal, (Summer 1978) pp. 4-5. (Box 105)
    - "Weather-Bound," Poverty," "Density," "Sunday at McDonald's," "Vehicle," and "Response," The Hudson Review, no. 4, vol. XXXI (Winter 1978-79) pp. 587-590. (Box 105)
    - "Why Is It Always the Way It Always Is," "Motion Which Disestablishes Organizes Everything," "Forerunners," "The Time Rate of Change," "Loving People," "Ah," "Slights of Sight," and "Fall's End" The Hudson Review, no. 2, vol. XL (Summer 1987) pp. 286-294. (Box 105)
    - "Winter Crop," Banyan, vol. 2, 1990, p. 10. (Box 105)
    - Ommateum, undated (Box 116)
      Poems by Archie Ammons. Illustration and Typography by Warren Luch and John Greiner
    - Expressions of Sea Level, 1963 (Box 133)
      Signed by Ammons. Some annotations.
    - Garbage, 1993, 1999 (Box 133)
      Signed by Ammons and dated 1999
    - The Selected Poems: The Expanded Edition, c. 1986 (Box 133)
      Signed by Ammons. With notes.
    - Lake Effect Country, 1983 (Box 133)
      Inscribed to Phyllis Ammons
    - Selected Poems by A.R. Ammons, 1968 (Box 133)
      Signed and annotated by Ammons.
    - Collected Poems, 1951-1971, 1972 (Box 133)
    - Sumerian Vistas, 1987 (Box 133)
      Note tipped in to front
    - Tape for the Turn of the Year, 1993, 1999 (Box 133)
      Signed and dated by Ammons 1999
    - Brink Road, 1996 (Box 133)
      Signed by Ammons. Note tipped in to back.
    - A Coast of Trees, 1981 (Box 133)
      Signed and annotated by Ammons 1999
    - Worldly Hopes, 1982 (Box 133)
      Signed and annotated by Ammons. Note tipped in to front.
  - Works about A. R. Ammons (criticism, reviews, interviews, Ph.D. Thesis, posthumous compilations) (Box 98-99, 106-108)
  - Works inscribed to A.R. Ammons (Box 109-111)
- Series XIII. Phyllis Ammons' Files
  - A.R. Ammons Chicago Review vol. 57, numbers 1/2 (Summer/Autumn), 2012 (Box 98)
    Phyllis Ammons' copy.
  - Genre: Forms of Discourse and Culture vol. 45, number 1 (Spring), 2012 (Box 98)
    Signed by Phyllis Ammons
  - "This is Just a Place: A Volume Dedicated to the Life and Work of A.R. Ammons Epoch vol. 52, number 3, 2004 (Box 98)
  - Book Cover materials (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Johnson Museum of Art (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - A.R. Ammons Art Shows (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Prizes, Tributes (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Archie - Old Receipts, Income, etc. (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Poems, Copies (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Poems, Articles, Translations (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Chapel Hill Library (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Navy Papers (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Rights and Agreements (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 2003-2006 (Box 127, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Joe Plumbo and Family (Phyllis' Brother), 1986 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    Folder also includes correspondence with the Hudson Review (1987)
  - Correspondence with Phyllis Ammoms, 2002-2007(bulk) (Box 127, Folder 12)
    Some correspondence with both Archie and Phyllis from 1982 and 1996
  - Gift to ECU (Greenville, NC) (Box 127, Folder 13)
  - W.W. Norton (Box 127, Folder 14)
  - Wake Forest Transcript (Box 127, Folder 15)
  - Post Surgery Diary Entries (Box 127, Folder 16)
  - Memorials (Box 127, Folder 17)
  - Epoch (Box 127, Folder 18)
  - Reviews (Box 127, Folder 19)
  - University of Michigan Press (Box 127, Folder 20)
  - W.W. Norton Royalty Statements (Box 127, Folder 21)
  - Norton (Box 127, Folder 22)
  - Norton Contracts (Box 127, Folder 23)
  - Agent (Box 127, Folder 24)
  - Papers and Permissions (Box 127, Folder 25)
  - Poems (Box 127, Folder 26-28)
  - Brink Road Manuscript (Box 127, Folder 29)
  - Bosh and Flapdoodle proofs (Box 129, Folder 1-3)
  - "Letters of AR Ammons to Phyllis Plumbo" draft (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Typed copies of A. R. Ammons' letters and journal and Correspondence with Phyllis Ammons, 2002-2012 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Articles on Ammons, 1982, 2007-2008, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Works by others, 2008, undated (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1984, 2002, 2009, undated (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1997-2001 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - The American Poet Magazine, 1998-1999 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - Ammons Obituaries (clippings), 2001 (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Archie Ammons, c. 1995 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - Archie Ammons Intro, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    Speech given at Goldwin Smith Hall, Cornell University introducing Archie Ammons
  - Emails between Archie and John Ammons, 1997-2001 (Box 129, Folder 14)
  - Copies of Poems for the A.R. Ammons issue of Epoch, undated (Box 129, Folder 15)
  - "New Collected Poems" Introductory Materials, undated (Box 129, Folder 16)
  - Handwritten poetry draft, undated (Box 129, Folder 18)
    written on an envelope
  - letters, cards, and poetry from Archie Ammons to Phyllis Ammons (Box 129, Folder 19)
  - Receipts, 1965 (Box 129, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous expense/income materials, 1963, 1978, undated (Box 129, Folder 21)
  - Income/Expenses, 1976, 1989-1998, undated (Box 129, Folder 22)
    Includes correspondence, clipping, a dairy entry and watercolor from 1976, and publication agreement
  - Income, 1988-1998 (Box 129, Folder 23)
    Cornell University Salary and income from publishers
  - Income, 1964-1965 (Box 129, Folder 24)
    Payment and salary documents
  - Legal/Financial, 1957-1959, 1964, 1967, 1982 (Box 129, Folder 25)
    Deed, Wills and Life Insurance documents (includes a copy of Archie Ammons' birth certificate
  - Bank and Investment Documents, 1959-1963, 1969-1981 (Box 129, Folder 26)
  - Wallet and Passport, 1947, c. 1998 (Box 129, Folder 27)
    Passport belonging to Phyllis Ammons from 1947 and wallet belonging to Archie Ammons c. 1998
  - Certificates of Smallpox Vaccination, 1967 (Box 129, Folder 28)
    For Archie, Phyllis and John
  - Fried, Philip, 1978-1999 (Box 129, Folder 29)
    Copies of Archie's letters to Philip Fried
  - Professor of Poetry Emeritus letter from Cornell University, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 30)
  - Tributes, celebrations, and events, 2006, 2010, undated (Box 129, Folder 31)
  - Harper's Weekly, 2013 (Box 129, Folder 32)
    Includes a poem by Ammons
  - Archie Ammons' Journals, 1998, 1999, 2000 (Box 129, Folder 33)
    Daily diaries
  - Notebook: Archie Ammons' memorial, 2001 (Box 129)
  - 14 notebooks belonging to Phyllis Ammons, 1991, 2001-2013, undated (Box 129)
    Various sizes
  - Letters from Phyllis to Archie Ammons [RESTRICTED], 1949-1950 (Box 130)